Hank Chen

User Experience Designer | U.S. Green Card

Enthusiastic and self-driven User Experience Designer. My love of design does not only stops at front end digital design. My background in architecture and industrial design has taught me the beauty of spatial design and physical product design. I thrive on simplicity as I believe less is more when it comes to design.

CONTACT

www.hankchen.us

480-840-5065

hankchen9299@gmail.com

SKILLS

User Experience Design

User Interface Design

User Research

User Story and Persona

Product Design

Prototyping

User Flows

Responsive Wireframe

Visual Mockups

3D modeling

TOOLS & SOFTWARES

HTML5 & CSS3

JavaScript

iQuery

Adobe Creative Suites

Invision

Draw.io

Balsamiq

Dreamweaver

Axure RP8

EDUCATION

Virginia Tech B. Architecture Minor Industrial Design May 2016

PROJECTS

Tape Measure

Web App Design

Self-initiated design project of a platform that improves daily tasks of the construction trade.

Analyzed research data and surveys of needs and experience gathered through former colleagues in the industry.

Designed the branding and logo through Illustrator and created the wireframes and prototype with Axure RP 8.

BlocShop

Ecommerce Website

Created wireframes and designed interfaces, logo, branding for an ecommerce platform after observing a potential market for student artists and individual artists.

Conducted research on targeted user (colleagues from school) for needs and desired features.

Developed the prototype of landing, browsing and product pages using HTML5, CSS3 and jQuery from scratch.

Paycrave

Mobile App Design

Designed the wireframes and interfaces of an Android mobile application as an alternative of Yelp specialized on food trucks with additional feature such as ordering and payments.

EXPERIENCE

History Factory, Freelance UX Designer

Oct 2017 - Present

Collaborated with a development team and in-house design team for a lobby exhibition at the corporate headquarter of a large utility company

Designed wireframes and digital contents for interactive touchscreens.

Bloc.io, Web Design Apprenticeship

Oct 2016 - Jul 2017

Developed rounded UIUX skills through a 36 week course with the mentorship of the co-founder of Made by Munsters.

Produced wireframes with Photoshop and prototypes with Invision for user testing.

Developed basic front-end interfaces with HTML5, CSS3, Java Script and jQuery.

Teel Construction, Assistant Superintendent

Jul 2016 - May 2017

Collaborated with Superintendent for the completion of projects. Supervised construction crew of 20 people and delivered a \$500,000 project on time as an assistant which in turn saved the company \$5,000 in staffing cost.

Proposed strategies to compete against large corporation in the acquisition of student talents resulted in decreased staffing cost, increased flexibility for senior superintendents and advertised the name of the company.